Burnaby, British Columbia

+1 (778) 706-0833 | pateljaimish629@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaimish-patel
GitHub: github.com/jaimishpatel41297

WEB DEVELOPER

Recent graduate with Computer and Information Systems degree and 1-year experience in Web Development. Experienced and knowledgeable to develop websites from scratch, handle backend, and deploying to cloud. Web developer with strengths in developing databases, user interfaces, Web-API, troubleshooting issues, and writing code. Seeking an opportunity to extend my Web Development skill and knowledge.

Professional Experience

Web Developer, Inspiro Infotech, Gujrat

July 2019 – October 2019

- Implemented changes to UX/UI of web and improved responsiveness of website by 70%
- Redesigned task and payment module using jQuery and JavaScript by introducing different UI and approaches to handle data.
- Wrote store procedures and SQL scripts for back-end.
- Inspected errors from spreadsheet and programmed solutions with listed task: Reduced customer support calls by 25%.

Web Developer, IT Futurz, Gujrat

December 2018 - May 2019

- Executed and worked on 3 web projects' UI/UX, web interfaces, websites, and CRM system.
- Partnered with developer to develop RESTful APIs and contributed to in-house UI library code.
- Communicated with clients to gather requirements, and designed websites that implement their core goal, resulting in improved customer experience engagement.

Web Developer Intern, YashWorld Products PVT LTD, Gujrat

May 2018 – June 2018

- Designed and developed dynamic web form, components, and web pages for websites in PHP.
- Evaluated and became knowledgeable in new concepts of web designing, technologies, and new standards in website development.

Technical Skills

Programming: C#,PHP, Java, Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Git

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Express, React, Vue, .NET Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, XML, ¡Query

Cloud: AWS, Google Cloud Platform Database: SQL, MongoDB

Education

Computer and Information System

December 2021

Douglas College, New Westminster, BC

Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, System Analysis & Design, Advanced Web Programming with JavaScript, and AJAX.

Bachelor of Information Technology

May 2019

Uka Tarsadia University, Bardoli, Gujarat

GPA: 7.9 / 10

Projects

Employee Management (Personal Project) <u>github.com/jaimishpatel41297/EmploymentManagement</u>

January 2022 - Present

JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, AWS, Heroku, GIT, Visual studio code

- Built full-stack application to manage employee information, and performance including features: attendance, leave, project, task, employee, meeting management, graphical presentation of data, clock in and clock out.
- Developed web services to handle data. React-router for navigation and deployed application to cloud.

Medical Service App (Academic Project) <u>github.com/jaimishpatel41297/MedicalService</u>
C#, Visual Studio, ADO.NET, SQL

September 2021 – December 2021

- Programmed a web application that allows patients to find doctors for treatment. Admin panel to contact patients, generate sales reports, manage doctors and treatment's details.
- Controller, validation, ADO.NET Entities' class library projects to handle, validate, and process backend data.

Diamond Management (Academic Project)

December 2018 – February 2019

PHP, Apache, SQL

• Developed a website that allows users to trade, search and order diamonds. Features of Admin panel: Inventory, user, and event management.